stand back up for conference on TV.
>> Uh [clears throat] yeah, just walk
through today.
>> Is that the first time you've done that
on a Wednesday?
>> Towards the end of the seasons, we
typically do that on Wednesdays.
>> How you feeling this week physically?
>> Yeah, I feel good. Obviously after games
you're a little sore, but better by the
day.
>> Ask you about your birthday.
>> I don't know what you mean by that. No.
But uh when you went back and looked at
the tape, maybe what was different about
maybe how you evaluated it this time
given how you felt about your
performance, do you think?
>> Different compared to what?
>> Just like was there anything different
or now saying [snorts]
>> um
I just made some I had some critical
mental mistakes that are
uncharacteristic of my play.
>> How do you kind of when when you've kind
of feel that way after a game, [snorts]
how do you not let that kind of seep
into the rest of the week and and kind
of have that snowball? Um,
it's not too hard. I've played I played
good football for a lot of years. I'm
not going to overreact to uh
an outlier game in my opinion. Um,
obviously you got to address it and talk
through the things that needed to be
better, but it's
certainly not a trend and
>> [snorts]
>> um not going to keep happening going
forward. Do you try to diagnose why the
mental errors happen? Is it does the
focus wayne a little bit when it's that
cold or is it the other things that were
you were talking about earlier in the
week?
>> Um, I think there I think a lot of
things went into it.
First and foremost, just
um mistakes by me, [snorts] but there
there were a lot of things.
>> Why are playing in the last three weeks
so important? Seems to be pretty average
about that. Why? Why does it matter to
you even though you guys are eliminated?
>> I like playing football. Um
for for the same reasons that I wanted
to push to come back from injury. Same
reasons I want to play this week. It
feels like
everything everybody's trying to do
everything in their power to make me not
play football. And I feel like I'm
fighting it like fighting everybody
else. Like I just want to play I just
want to play ball. That's all I want to
do. There's been a lot of speculation
after last week just in general [snorts]
about your comments last week. How much
do you love playing football and have
you ever thought about not playing?
I mean, you you think about it, but you
think about a lot of different things
and in your life, just like everybody
does, you think about all different
possibilities that could happen. Um, I'm
going to be playing for a long time. I
expect to play for a long time and I
expect to play well and consistently
great for a long time.
>> Is anybody in the building trying to get
you to not play?
>> No.
>> What's it like hearing all your fans are
like listen
Joe? How frustrating is it to hear that
given all the work that you put in? I
mean, what's your reaction when people
kind of say stuff like that?
>> It's just noise to me. Um,
obviously fans are going to have their
opinions about what their favorite teams
should or shouldn't do. That's what
makes this sport great
and
that's why revenues are so high and
that's why we get paid so much because
the fans care a lot about
what we do and who we are and
all the things that come with that. So
that's [snorts] part of it. That's
something that you have to
number one embrace. Number two, take
with a grain of salt a lot. Um but
that's comes with the territory.
>> Fans have their opinions, Joe, but you
have your opinion and obviously yours
carries a lot more weight in the
building. A report out this week that
Zach's going to probably be here for the
next two seasons. Probably not going to
be any changes in the front office. I
think you've been on record before
saying that, you know, status quo isn't
enough if we're not playing to our
standard. How do you come to grips with
those two realities in your mind? Number
one, I think I think we have great
coaches. I think we're consistently put
in good positions to
make plays and and do our best.
Obviously,
um there's good games and bad games,
just like players have good games and
bad games. Um, but I have [snorts] a lot
of confidence in in everybody that's
putting together the plans for us week
in and week out. That's not to say that
uh
changes don't need need to be made. Not
saying personnel or people. I'm just
saying uh you know what we've been doing
hasn't worked the last couple years. So,
you know, we have to think outside the
box and get creative about um where we
go from here. Do you think that from
your conversations in years past
[snorts] with ownership and Duke and
Zach that the organization would be
willing to take a look at it and and
evaluate it for what it is in terms of
change might be needed in some areas?
>> Yeah, we all we all want to win. We all
want to do whatever it takes to to win.
and we [snorts] have a lot of smart
people here that
um
know how to
put the right people and decision makers
in place to
try to be our best.
You know, we've done it before. We'll
have to do it again.
>> Have you voiced your opinion to them?
front office and ownership is
>> we have we have constant communication a
lot of conversations
uh that's a pretty vague question I
think
uh
>> you can be as specific as you want
>> yeah I know I know you get I know I
can't [laughter]
um
there there's there's convers there's
always conversations being had about
different perspectives uh about what's
happening and what's going on that are
being shared.
>> Is there one change that you feel like
would be partic that you particularly
care about that you feel like would be
beneficial that is that the top of your
list? It's
>> tough to say right now.
>> It's tough to say right now.
>> With the big changes, would you expect
them to
talk to you about them if they were
having conversations about that about
big potential changes?
head coach, director of plan, stuff like
that.
>> Uh I I appreciate being informed of
of of decisions that are being made. Um
that's not to say that I need to be
involved in the decision-m processes,
but uh I enjoy being kept up to date
about thought processes and and
decision-m trees.
popular fan sentiment is that with you
guys missing the playoffs three years
ago that your prime could be wasted
because of you haven't been in the
playoffs and hadn't had a chance to get
back to where you were. When you think
about the changes that we're all talking
to you about, does that weigh on you
where, you know, you turned 29 and and
you've talked about, you know, wanting
to play for a long time, but do you
think about that and and really take it
for what it is and hope that the
organization
see that you hope you get as many years
as you can here, but right now the
nucleus is tomorrow
get yourself back into the playoffs.
Yeah, obviously we we haven't been where
we want to be the last three years.
A big part of that is injuries on my
end. I've played one full season. I
played four games this year.
It's hard to make an impact on a on a
season when when you play four games.
So,
that's an emphasis. Obviously,
you need to figure out a way to to be
available for for everybody here.
Um,
and so as far as what what I can
control, that's that's something that uh
is on top of mind for me.
>> When the Bengals played the Dolphins in
2019, were you aware of what that result
could have meant for you personally at
the time? [sighs and gasps]
>> I think so.
Um, I think we're at the point in in the
year for me where
I kind of expected to go where I was
going to go at that point and um, I feel
like I had thoughts like that. It was a
long time ago now. U, but I I believe I
remember I remember thinking something
like that.
>> Did you watch any of that game at all?
>> I think we showed the highlights in a
team meeting.
>> Okay.
>> One of those days.
something like that.
>> Why why why did that why did those
highlights end up coming up?
>> I think it was in a situational
>> meeting because there were a lot it was
a crazy game and there were a lot of uh
situational
teaching moments uh in that one. So I
think we I think we were showing those.
Joe, I would imagine there are
organizations in this league that
either might not appreciate a player
being so outspoken publicly about
different issues um or just wouldn't
want to hear it. uh ho how valuable to
you is it that you're in a place where
you feel comfortable to
solicit feedback from them but also like
that you know um ownership
but also uh comfortable enough to to
speak your mind. How how valuable is
that?
>> Yeah, it's um
I've never had any conversations like
that. I also I don't think I've said
anything crazy. Um
I
I share what I'm comfortable sharing. Um
sometimes vague, sometimes specific. I
don't think
I think a lot in my life I
fairly quiet and so
I often don't say
a lot
and so
[snorts] people then like to
fill in the gaps here and there if that
makes sense. Um, [clears throat]
I think
I think about what I say a lot
and [snorts]
don't necessarily care
what comes of it. Um, I don't think
I'm smart enough not to say
things are going to put people in bad
positions. Um,
and I'm smart enough to know what to say
and what not to say and I think
everybody in the building trusts that.
Do you accept the the premise that you
are in your prime right now or when you
see quarterbacks playing well under 30s,
do you think your prime can still be in
front of you?
>> Well, I think people have proven that
you can play at a high level for a long
time. Um,
Tom Brady proved it, Pton Manning proved
it, Drew Brees proved it, Aaron Rogers
is proving it, Joe Flacco has proven it.
Uh, and so, you know, I want to be in
the conversations with people like that.
So,
>> [snorts]
>> um, and I do everything that I need to
to do for my body to prepare it for
these
games and for long-term success. So, I
plan on doing it for a long time at a
high level.
>> On Sunday, you said not that far. when
asked how close this organization was to
getting back to those big stages. Why do
you think you guys are are not that far?
>> Well, we have young guys that are
getting better. I think we have really
smart coaches.
Um,
we have a lot of highly talented people
that go out and perform at a high level
on Sundays, week in and week out.
Um,
you know, it's hard for me to
it's hard for me to talk about the
totality of the season this year because
I was removed from it for so long. And,
[snorts]
you know, I really h I haven't had a
season. I've played four games and
that's frustrating to me. and um
kind of it made me feel like I was on
the outside looking in for a lot of it
cuz that's what happens. Um
and so I'm just getting my feet wet
again with all this and uh it feels good
but you know I [clears throat] feel
confident in the people that we have
that we have here. In your mind, do you
think you guys would be right there had
you just stayed healthy or [snorts] do
you not even let yourself go down that
>> a lot of whatifs in that situation?
>> Obviously, you and Tua are going to be
linked together for for a long time
because we all in the same draft class
and having the 19 season Shel did. Just
out of curiosity, do you think it's that
everyone talks about that game y'all had
against Bama in 19 how stacked those
rosters were? Do you think that's going
to be possible again given the way
college football's changed?
No, I think that's part of
the change in landscape with NIL. I
think you see a lot of different teams
in the playoffs year in and year out.
It's not just, you know, the Alabama's,
Ohio States and LSUs and Clemson's and
Oklahoma's anymore. Yeah, those teams
are still making it, some of them not.
But
with the expanded playoff with NIO, with
all these different
rules now,
there's
the town is so much more dispersed
across all these different schools. And
I think that's been for the most part
good for the onfield
product and competitiveness. Obviously,
um
there's downsides to that certainly
off the field, but um I think for the
most part on the field it's been good.
>> There's only so much speculation. I just
Is there ever is there any world in your
mind where you're not the quarterback of
the Bengals next year?
>> I could I couldn't see I can't see that.
No.
Have you ever both thought about the
possibility of not being the quarterback
here during your career or
>> you think about a lot of things?
>> When you look at quarterbacks over the
course of their time, great ones,
Peyton, Brady,
you kind of have to understand that you
never know what this league will bring.
And what did you learn from watching how
their careers unfolded?
>> Yeah, a lot of crazy things happen every
year. [snorts]
Um, Micah Parsons got traded
right before the se right before the
season, I think this year.
That is a something I hadn't seen in a
long time in the NFL. So, crazy things
can happen.
Joe, when you I know you say these last
three games are city, what kind of
meaning do you think they carry for, you
know, guys outside of the core that you
have [snorts] that show that they can be
part of, you know, the plans and what's
going to be a big offseason to help you
guys get back to where you feel like you
can be.
>> Yeah. Anytime you get the opportunity to
strap up the pads and put the cleats on
and go in the front of the world and
prove your worth, prove all the hard
work that you've put in,
prove that you're improving week to
week. That's what we're all trying to
do. We're trying to to get better and
better ourselves.
And
we have three opportunities to to do
that. Um,
you know, when I wanted to come back,
obviously you want to make the playoffs
and you want to make a run and all of
that, but um, that was kind of tertiary
in in my mind. I just wanted to
get back out there and play and put on a
show and try to play well and produce.
>> You ever cross paths with Quinn yours at
any point?
>> All right.
>> I assume you've seen the news where he's
supposed to start. You think back at all
to your first career start in a
different situation. Heisman winner,
number one pick except after unpick, but
just how much you had not been swimming
that first game.
>> Yeah, certainly different situations. Um
I had a full off season to
full off season to prepare.
He's getting thrown in there in week
um with basically one week of practice
as the starter. So that's certainly not
the easiest position to to be in, but
that's a situation that you can find
yourself in.
>> How different is the defense of the
Dolphins from the Ravens?
>> Um, pretty similar scheme.
They like to
they like to use Minka kind of like the
the Ravens use Kyle Hamilton.
So, we we'll see if Minka ends up
playing or not, but you always got to be
aware of of where he's at. I think their
front is very disruptive, explosive.
They play well together. Um, so just
like every week, it's going to be a
challenge.
>> What's it been like over the last week
people dissecting the mood of a presser?
It seems What's that what's it been like
to kind of see people needs that much on
kind of how your disposition's been over
the last seven days?
>> That's how it goes. That's how it goes.
Certainly
had some texts that didn't make a lot of
sense to me um after all that, but
it is what it is.
>> You going to tell us what was in the
Pokemon box?
>> I haven't opened I didn't open yet. I
don't know if I should open it or not
yet. I think I have to figure out if
this is something that
might be more valuable in 10 years if
you don't open it than otherwise. So, I
got some research to do.
>> Since you're talking about presents,
have you figured out what you're giving
the offensive line yet?
>> Have I ever told you guys what I'm going
to get him? [laughter]
>> Well, not for me.
>> What are you giving it to?
>> Um, next Monday.
>> Did they ask for guns again?
>> No, [clears throat] they didn't ask for
guns this time. [laughter]
They know better.
>> Thanks, Joe.
See?